You must find it strange.
Why was I poisoned by you
but still managed to survive?
When you assassinated Zhang Ruipu,
you coated the blade
with Twilight Grass Poison, right?
I should have been killed
in one strike.
Unfortunately, I was exposed
to Twilight Grass three years ago
and had already developed antibodies.
Just like how those inoculated
against smallpox are immune to it.
That's why I didn't die.
But the poison didn't wear off.
It confused my mind
and caused hallucinations.
Actually, I...
have never left this room.
I have a question.
Why are you hunting down people
from the Archives on the Nan'an?
[Archives: The Nanyang Mystery]
[Episode 7]
You're just a cripple.
When did you know
you were poisoned?
The first time I saw Chen Xifeng,
I had my suspicions.
The people from the Panhua Reef Case
appeared on the Nan'an.
They have such a terrible stench.
Ordinary people couldn't possibly miss it.
But they had no reaction at all.
So I confirmed then
that something was wrong with me.
The smell of cured meat?
And later, I realized
someone was watching me,
wanting me to die on the ship.
These are all hallucinations.
Everything I see is not real.
Hailou is not even here.
It has always been just me.
Ten,
eleven,
twelve,
thirteen.
The patrol light flashes every 13 seconds.
You understand this feeling best,
don't you?
I'm just a burden.
You are not a burden.
Stop messing around. You'll die here.
Then let me die.
If I become a burden to you,
I'd rather die.
You are my brother.
You must stay alive.
Stay alive!
I can't.
I don't want to live like this.
Help me.
I shouldn't live like this.
Kill me.
Help me.
These are all hallucinations.
Everything I see is unreal.
Zhang Hailou.
You are so lucky.
Lend me some luck.
Why was I poisoned by you
but still managed to survive?
Ten,
eleven,
twelve,
thirteen.
You really are a monster.
You're just like me now,
unable to walk.
Now it's my turn to ask you!
Why are you trying to kill the people
of the Archives?
Who gave the order?
[If the pitcher plant plan succeeds,]
[wipe out every member of the Archives.]
If the pitcher plant plan succeeds,
wipe out every member of the Archives
and proceed immediately to the next phase.
This is 20 years of my life's work.
There must be no mistakes.
The content of this letter...
is true?
This has been going on for 20 years?
Why are you trying to kill the people
of the Archives?
What's your next step?
Spit it out!
You think you're smart.
Actually...
we are all just pawns.
The Nan'an
is like a giant pitcher plant.
You flies from the Archives
cannot escape.
You're no different.
I need to find Zhang Hailou
as soon as possible.
Cheer up, Fast Gun.
Come,
have a drink first.
This drink is on me.
Sit.
How did you manage to do it?
With this.
What is this?
Poison?
It's a kind of herb.
After touching human skin,
it produces symptoms similar
to toxic weed poisoning.
It hurts and itches.
Combined with my
excellent makeup skills,
ordinary people can't tell the difference.
But I have to thank a good friend of mine
who helped me a lot.
[Nanyang Daily]
The red rash drawn with this pigment
cannot be wiped off
by ordinary reagents.
It can only be wiped off
with my specially formulated
alcohol reagent.
How is it, Fast Gun?
I know you are very interested
in my next plan.
Feel free to ask.
I can tell you everything now.
I don't care about your bullshit plan.
I just want to go back.
[Countdown: 12 hours]
Actually,
my plan is very simple.
It's to draw the snake out of its hole.
First,
I will randomly
choose some passengers
and use the ink
mixed with the special herb
to draw red rashes on their arms.
But adult Chinese males will be excluded.
Those warlord soldiers at Panhua Reef
are likely the culprits.
They are all adult Chinese males.
Please, doctor!
[Countdown: 4 hours]
Save us!
If the culprits find out
that the toxic weed is spreading
and can be cured,
they will definitely come
to see what's going on.
On the other hand,
those who I drew rashes on
and didn't seek treatment
are also suspicious.
Doctor, save us, doctor!
Why won't you let us in?
Let us in!
Doctor!
Why can they go in?
What I need to do next
is to observe these people—
who came
and who didn't.
O Lord Almighty!
We must face misfortune!
Only the children who believe in God
will be blessed!
O Lord Almighty, please bless us!
Bless us!
They're gone!
I'm cured!
Thank you, thank you!
Thank you!
Look! I'm cured!
Great!
Shh.
What the hell are you doing?
Catching robbers.
How?
Simply put, bluff them
and see their reactions.
It's like throwing a bomb into a cesspool
to see if there are maggots.
What are you talking about?
Are you out of ideas?
Next one.
Next.
Bless us.
Go in now.
I'm cured!
Bless us.
Thank you, thank you!
Any maggots? Where are they?
Maybe
this cesspool...
is relatively clean.
Yeah, why are there no maggots?
What other plans do you have?
[Countdown: 15 minutes]
We're running out of time!
Look, look!
The Nan'an is about to depart.
And your time is up!
I need to get ready.
Do you mind?
I...
Okay.
See you later.
Don't go anywhere.
[Countdown: 10 minutes]
Mentor, Shrimpie.
[Countdown: 9 minutes]
[Countdown: 8 minutes]
Am I exposed?
[Countdown: 7 minutes]
Impossible.
Why aren't the culprits
interested in this?
Did someone see through my disguise?
That can't be, Mentor.
You know my disguise skills best.
Ordinary people can't tell the difference.
How is that possible?
Then why didn't the culprits
take the bait?
Is there any other way
to lure the culprits out?
Oh yes, baby.
The time has come.
I'm running out of time.
[Countdown: 4 minutes]
Mentor, Shrimpie,
take care of yourselves.
I'll go find a place to hide.
No.
Once the ship sets sail,
I won't be able to return
to the South Seas for months.
[Countdown: 2 minutes]
Should I just get off the ship
and go home now?
Don't play these useless little tricks.
By the time you came here,
they had already left.
And my boss's men are watching you.
We will have eyes and ears around you
all the time.
If you do anything unrelated
to the investigation,
your friends
will die.
[First Class] [Second Class]
Wait.
There are doctors on board.
You can see them for any issues.
With the toxic weed outbreak on the ship,
everyone came to see what was happening.
Why didn't the ship doctors come?
There are symptoms
of Twilight Grass Poison on the ship.
Some passengers who can't see the Dukun
would definitely
go to the ship doctors first.
There's a toxic weed outbreak on board.
The ship doctor should lock down the ship
and not let it sail.
But he had no reaction at all.
The ship doctor is the culprit!
Oh my.
I knew I could count on you.
I'm going to the infirmary.
Your time is up.
I know.
But you're 2 seconds early!
Fast Gun!
Wait, wait!
The robbers have been found!
They are in the infirmary!
They are the ship doctors!
Steven,
you don't want
these 2 days of hard work
to be in vain, do you?
How dare you mention the last 2 days!
There were no robbers at all!
Everyone.
When Steven cries,
he's a...
Shit!
I almost caught the culprits.
[Bowne]
You ugly thing.
Why are you haunting me?
[He Jianxi, accountant]
Who are you?
You...
Stowaway?
I didn't stow away.
I came to use the toilet and take a nap,
but accidentally fell into the sea.
I barely managed to climb back up.
I'm "poop-sleepy".
I get sleepy when I poop.
Stop talking nonsense.
Stowing away is a serious crime.
If you get caught,
I'll be implicated
and thrown into the sea as well.
You're crazy.
How did you manage to climb up?
[Public Toilet]
What are you doing?
Let go!
That's my hard-earned money!
Stowaway...
Stop.
Show me your ticket.
Then I'll just buy a ticket now.
It's an unlicensed ship.
You've been robbing Chinese passengers.
Aren't you afraid the Sea Plague
will find out?
That Plague isn't that well-informed.
Besides, this guy has no companions.
If we throw him into the sea
off the back of the ship,
no one will notice.
Since you saw this,
I guess I'll just take another life.
In that case,
I'll have no choice but to...
Show your ticket.
Spare us.
Sir,
this is my cousin.
We are the only two remaining heirs
of our family.
If you kill us both,
our bloodline will end.
Sir,
we will absolutely not tell anyone
what you did today.
Please spare our worthless lives.
Sir.
You didn't
rob us.
It's my gift to you.
Just take it.
Rest assured.
The Sea Plague
won't know about this either.
Disasters are rampant these days.
You don't want to
bring down divine punishment, do you?
You little brat.
You're too smart.
Alright.
You're not like those
who value money over their lives.
You know how to show respect.
I am the Two-ear Dragon.
Call me Dragon.
Dragon.
On this ship,
I've got you covered.
I'll keep the money for now.
I'll make arrangements for you later.
Okay, okay.
Hurry.
Get them a private room.
-Thank you.
-And...
What's your name?
Salty Zhang.
Hurry up and get a ticket for Salty Zhang.
Without a ticket, I can't protect you.
Cousin, enjoy yourself.
How pathetic.
These people barely escaped death.
If they act tough again,
their lives will be over.
Why did you give him my stuff?
That's my hard-earned money!
We shouldn't give in to people like that!
You have quite a temper.
[Nan'an]
Where did that guy in the wheelchair go?
Why is there no scent of Hailou at all?
The Nan'an,
speed 12 knots.
The Bowne,
speed 6 knots.
The speed gap between the two ships
is huge.
Even if I hijack the Bowne,
I wouldn't be able to catch up.
You are hijacking the ship?
Shut up.
Who are you?
I don't know you.
Money.
My money.
[004]
What?
Are you going to seek justice
from the ship tyrant?
Are you getting off the ship then?
If you go and cause trouble,
will they let you stay on this ship?
Can you stay alive?
Stop trying to get yourself killed,
alright?
Life is so precious.
Forget about the money.
I just saw it.
You still have quite a bit of money,
don't you?
How could you go through my things?
Compared to many on this ship,
you are considered well-off.
This ticket is a one-way trip to hell.
The money you spent is worth it.
Stop messing around.
Hide this money.
Let me ask you something.
Where is this ship going?
Jinfan.
Jinfan?
Can a small ship like this reach Jinfan?
As far as I know, these unlicensed ships,
once out at sea,
will rob you blind.
They sell the women
and throw the men into the sea.
That was in the past.
Ever since the legend of the Sea Plague,
such things haven't happened again.
That's how my brother went to Jinfan.
I'm going to Jinfan to find him.
You know a lot about the Plague?
Haven't you heard?
The Sea Plague is very formidable.
I heard he wears a mask
and specifically kills those
evil sailors
who rob and kill Chinese passengers.
I heard he has a blade in his mouth
to slice open the mouths
of those bad guys.
Ever since the Plague
appeared in the South Seas,
Chinese passengers on this route
have been respected much more.
Well said.
You're bleeding!
Keep it down.
You...
What's the fuss about bleeding?
Why are you so nervous?
I'm not nervous.
You...
You're a wanted criminal?
What are you talking about?
I'm a victim.
You're a victim,
so what are you afraid of?
I'm being hunted by my enemies.
My parents are dead.
My sister is still in their hands.
They are extremely powerful.
Now they've hired the police to catch me.
How can I not be nervous?
I have to save my sister.
Wh-Wh-Wh-
[004]
Stop it.
You don't need to worry about this.
The situation is very complicated now.
Look.
I got this from my enemy.
They want to sacrifice my sister's life
to this thing.
Eight years old.
She is 8.
My sister is only 8 years old.
And she has lost our parents.
I am all she has left.
Can you give me
and my sister a way out?
Take this to stop the bleeding first.
What?
Take it.
Although I don't understand
what you are saying,
I think you must be
in some kind of trouble
and need help.
Stop the bleeding first.
Your life matters.
By the way,
I also have a bottle of painkillers here.
Take some first.
It should help.
You actually bought that?
I mean, all along my way,
I've been all alone.
No one has been willing to help me.
You are the first.
That's nice.
I understand you.
I have family too.
They are waiting for me far away.
Besides, I think you have a kind face.
You don't really look like a murderer.
Right?
Moreover,
if what you said is true,
wouldn't I really be killing your sister?
Cousin.
I'd like to ask you for one more favor.
What is it?
With this injury,
it's really hard for me
to get around right now.
Could you help me ask the sailor
for the Bowne's route?
I need to plan how to save my sister.
I have the Bowne's route.
Look, the Bowne
sets sail at dusk.
It leaves from Balongzhou Pier,
heads out into the open sea,
and goes straight to Jinfan.
The Nan'an has already set sail.
But it has to reach
Ningcheng Deep Water Port first,
then head back into the inland sea
to return to Xiacheng.
The Nan'an?
Are you talking about a luxury cruise ship
that also departs from Balongzhou Pier?
I think I saw it before I boarded.
My sister is on the Nan'an.
I have to go save her.
Your sister is on the Nan'an?
These two ships will both be at
the junction of the inland and open seas,
sharing an overlapping route.
That means these two ships
will pass on this route
at the same time.
The speed of the Nan'an
is 12 knots.
But its route is much longer
than the Bowne's.
The arrival time
should be around 6 or 7 in the evening.
The Bowne's speed is 6 knots,
so the time
it reaches the junction will be...
4:28 PM today.
The exact arrival time of the Nan'an
will be 6:36 PM.
Why are you drawing this?
You are not thinking about jumping
into the sea and swimming there, are you?
Cousin,
you are so smart.
So,
I just need to reach
the junction
before 6:36 tonight,
and I can get on the Nan'an
to save my sister.
Wait.
Who on earth did you offend?
Gang members?
Pirates?
People on this ship like to gamble.
Cousin,
I need you to lend me some more money.
I promise I'll pay you back.
There's no way I'll lend you more.
Pay up!
-Pay up!
Hurry up!
Oh no.
My money!
Eight of bamboos.
I won! I won again!
A flush.
Give me the money.
Salty, I really underestimated you.
Look at your amazing luck.
You're the lucky one, Dragon.
Here.
Take it.
That's not appropriate.
Take it, Dragon.
My cousin
is not very sensible.
Please be understanding.
From now on,
your cousin's business is my business.
Give me my money back!
Look, speak of the devil.
Turmeric?
He's cheating.
He's a scammer.
His hands smell of turmeric.
He rubbed turmeric
on the tiles to mark them.
How could you do such a thing?
Everyone here earns their money
through hard work.
By doing this, they will die!
Do you believe the Plague
will take you away?
Great.
You've been cheating?
I didn't cheat.
You're the ones cheating.
You're the ones
who rubbed the turmeric on the tiles.
I just got a little
on my hands from the tiles.
Cousin, don't you have a good nose?
Why don't you take a sniff?
See if the smell on his hands
is stronger than mine.
Why did you hit me?
These guys were scamming in Balai.
They made enough money there,
and now they're on this ship
to continue scamming in Jinfan.
These scumbags.
If you don't kick them off the ship,
just wait for bad luck.
You believe his nonsense?
Take the money.
I'm returning it to you with interest.
We met scammers!
Exactly. This brat lives in a compartment,
while we live in a common room.
At his age,
where did he get the money
to live in a compartment?
He must have scammed all that money.
Okay.
I won't meddle in this.
Let's listen to Dragon.
Dragon, be the judge here.
Dragon.
No, no.
It's your grudge.
You solve it yourselves.
Solve it yourselves.
Dragon...
So disloyal?
Let the Sea Plague take you!
That's right! Take the money!
Throw him into the sea!
There's the Plague in the sea!
The Plague has a blade in his mouth!
Let the Plague cut off his stinking mouth!
Hello, everyone.
Didn't you want to see the Plague?
The Plague is here!
He is the Sea Plague?
Really?
The Plague! The Sea Plague!
The Sea Plague! The Sea Plague!
How could it be?
The hero I admire,
the Sea Plague,
the knight
who protects the Chinese passengers,
is actually...
him.
The Sea Plague! The Sea Plague!